

# **Amanuel Tesfay**

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

+251914131366 amanueltesfay99@gmail.com https://www.amanueltesfay.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/am anuel-tesfay-576b121a2/

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am an Energetic Operations Support with more than 3 years of experience resolving complex customer inquiries. Passionate about building strong customer relationships, driving brand loyalty, and increasing customer engagement I am highly motivated to continue learning and improving my craft.

## **SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES**

- Problem-solving.
- · Team working skills, Active listening
- · Customer Service Skills.
- Communication
- Time management
- Proficient in using freshdesk and atlassian jira software

## **CERTIFICATION & VOLUNTEER WORK**

# Full-stack developer Evangadi Networks

Online courses provided by Evangadi Networks covered HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, media- query, Javascript, Node.Js, React.Js, Mysql, Git, Git-hub, and express.Js with projects.

## Volunteer Administrator

Zewditu Meshesha (philanthropist)
Collaborated with a team of 15+ volunteers to raise funds, and support kids who lost their parents.

## Microsoft talent training Certificate

Gebeya Talent agency

Online program provided by Microsoft company covered C#, JAVA, and DevOps and how to build an inbound marketing strategy.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## **Intern Software Engineer**

Paga payment

August 2022 to Present

- Developing applications (coding, programming)
- Debugging and testing code
- · Documenting and testing new software applications
- Researching, investigating, and fixing a wide range of technical issues
- · Collaborating with senior leaders
- · Approaching problems and creating solutions
- Proactively learning about new technologies

# Operations Support (Customer Experience)

Paga payment

September 2021 to Present

- Ensure the delivery of excellent customer service when assisting customers and agents in a professional and efficient manner.
- Receive and respond to emails from customers and agents using applications like Freshdesk.
- Identifying and escalating priority issues to the appropriate quarters for assistance.

## **Customer Support Specialist**

Apposit

February 2019 to September 2021

- Responsible for taking control of and resolving complex and escalated customer-related issues.
- Manages testing communications for all project work assigned, and documents and manages project issues.
- Works closely with software developers and support teams to foster high customer satisfaction and generate profit.

#### Network administrator

Sheba University Collage

January 2019 to March 2019

- Maintaining existing software and hardware and upgrading any that have become obsolete.
- Monitoring computer networks and systems to identify how performance can be improved.
- · working with IT support personnel.
- Identifying and solving any problems that arise with computer networks and systems.
- Consulting with clients to specify system requirements and design solutions. Budgeting for equipment and assembly costs.

## LANGUAGE & SOFTWARE SKILLS

Tigrinya: NativeAmharic: FluentEnglish: Fluent

• OS Linux, Windows

 MS SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, media-query

· Javascript, Node.Js, React.Js, express.Js,

• java, java Springboot, C#, C++, PHP

· Git-hub and Git.

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

## **Sheba University Collage**

Ethiopia, Mekelle Bachelor's Degree in Computer sciences, with GPA 3.06 September 2014 - July 2018

# Ayder secondary and preparatory school

Ethiopia, Mekelle Completed secondary and preparatory school September 2011 - July 2014

## **REFERENCES**

Bethlehem Girma Project manager | excellerent +251932201043 | betyy.gi@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Fanuel Yemane Project manager | Paga +251912619047| fanu236@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Hareg Embaye Project manager | Paga +251962230124 | hareg.embaye65@gmail.com Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Mahfuz Bedru Head Department of Information Technology | Sheba university college +251914727689 | mafbefru@gmail.com Mekelle, Ethiopia